Everything is based on memory.
Warfare is a war, action film directed by Ray Mendoza.
A platoon of Navy SEALs embarks on a dangerous mission in Ramadi, Iraq, with the
chaos and brotherhood of war retold through their memories of the event.
Ray, played by D'Pharaoh Woon-A-Tai.
Erik, played by Will Poulter.
Elliott, played by Cosmo Jarvis.
Tommy, played by Kit Connor.
John, played by Finn Bennett.
Frank, played by Taylor John Smith.
Warfare is a 2025 war film written and directed by Ray Mendoza and Alex Garland.
Based on Mendoza's experiences during the Iraq War as a U.S.
Navy SEAL, the film depicts an encounter on 19
November 2006 after the Battle of Ramadi.
The script is drawn from the testimonies of the platoon
members and is presented in real time.
It stars an ensemble cast including D'Pharaoh Woon-A-Tai as Mendoza, alongside Will Poulter,
Cosmo Jarvis, Kit Connor, Finn Bennett, Joseph Quinn, and Charles Melton.
The film is dedicated to platoon member Elliott Miller (portrayed by Jarvis in
the film), who lost his leg and ability to speak in the incident.
Warfare premiered at the Music Box Theatre in Chicago on 16 March 2025, and was released in the
United States by A24 on 11 April 2025, and in the United Kingdom on 18 April.
The film received positive reviews and has grossed $33.6 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of u.s. navy seal,
docudrama, iraq war, platoon, real time.